# Victoria Fredericksen

<u>victoriafreder@gmail.com</u> | Houston, TX <u>LinkedIn Profile</u> | <u>GitHub Profile</u>

# **SUMMARY**

Meticulous telecommuter with more than 4 years of experience working remotely and using a variety of virtual tools such as PowerPoint, Excel, and Zoom to satisfy client needs, leading to over 20 client contract renewals. Quickly learned technical skills needed to build websites, including HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, as well as soft skills such as teamwork, communication, and detail orientation.

## **SKILLS**

- Microsoft PowerPoint
- Microsoft Excel
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript

- Collaborative
- Communication
- Adaptable
- Adept
- Detail oriented

# **PROJECTS**

Random Name Generator

• Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

# Victoria Fredericksen's Portfolio Site

• Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Generation Junior Web Developer Program**

- Participated in an 21 week Junior Web Developer program spending over 350 hours learning how web development works: from the fundamentals of JavaScript, programming fundamentals, developer tools, and the behavioral skills and mindsets needed to be successful as a web developer.
- Took the lead on a project using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to build a responsive website that creates a to-do list.

# **International Open Academy**

Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages Certificate

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Bergen English | January 2020-Current

English Tutor

- Conducting regular online classes for over 50 students during one-on-one and group classes.
- Recording concise and descriptive notes in student files in order to convey progress to parents and update the computer system.
- Developing rapport with students, leading to over 20 contract renewals.
- Consulting with 9 other members of a team about student progress and necessary changes to curriculum.

#### Golden Voice English | July 2017-October 2021

English Tutor

- Learned three different kinds of software to facilitate online lessons, including Zoom, ClassIn, and Microsoft PowerPoint.
- Taught an average of 30 classes per week, each 25 minutes long.
- Contributed to team meetings and shared suggestions to enhance learning content, many of which were implemented.

# **Kumon Learning Center of Bentonville, Arkansas** | September 2015-March 2017 *Tutor*

- Assisted in tutoring over 30 children in Mathematics and Reading subjects, leading to the majority increasing school grades by 10%.
- Created a schedule of students entering and leaving the classroom, and helped students to complete class work on time.
- Trained 4 newly hired tutors to grade homework and classwork, improving grading time by 20%.

## **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

Volunteer Teacher | March 2013-Current

- Dedicating an average of 70 hours per month teaching individuals valuable principles to help improve life skills and interpersonal relationships.
- Learning other languages (Pohnpeian and West African Pidgin) to communicate with minority ethnic groups in the southwest Missouri and Houston, Texas areas.
- Adapting methods during COVID-19 pandemic to contact persons through hand-written letters, phone calls, videoconferencing, and text messaging.